

## LENCER ONDIJO

## UX Designer & Researcher

An educator turned UX Designer with 10+ years of international experience in the Higher Education Industry. Empathy, problem solving, research and writing are my core competencies. I design apps that are learnable and impact lives

1794215767

Prototyping

Data Analysis

Wireframing

**User Surveys** 

Sketch

Balsamiq

MaxQDA

Figma

**SPSS** 

**SOFT** 

Problem Solving

Communication

**Design Thinking** 

Analytical Skills

Critical Thinking

LANGUAGES

English - Native

German - C1

Photoshop

Articulate

■ londijo@gmail.com

https://lencerondijo.com/

Frankfurt am Main

EDUCATION SKILLS

User Experience Design (Certification)

User Experience Design (Certification)

User Research

User Flows
CareerFoundry - Online Project based Design

Completed 400+ hours of project based and mentor guided UX design course

focussing on Competitive Analysis, Research Methods, Information Architecture,

Competitor Analysis

Interaction Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Usability Testing, A/B Preference Testing and Design for Accessibility. See my course project: My Grad Link

Management Systems in Higher Education

Johannes Gutenberg Universität 2017 - 2020

PhD Candidate

Usability Test
Topic: Investigating the role of Organisational Culture in Performance

Technische Universität Dresden 2014 - 2016 User Interviews

MA: Vocational Education & Personnel Capacity Building

TOOLS

Thesis Project: Curriculum Design and Conceptualisation: Organisational

Culture in Higher Education Module

TOOLS

Adobe XD

Kenyatta University 2006 - 2010

Bachelor of Education

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance UX Designer; Learning Management Platforms 12/2019 - Present

Created personas, mapped user flows, and documented user requirements

 Created information architecture and user flow diagrams to improve the website's infrastructure, features, and hierarchy for clients

Liaised with product mangers in crafting brand strategies

Conducted UX research and usability tests for clients

Frankfurt School of Finance & Management 08/2017 - 08/2019

Admissions Officer, Pre-Experience Master Programmes

Created the on-boarding course guide for incoming students using Canvas
Collaborated with management in classroom crafting

Monitored and updated Full Fabric- the online admission platform

Selected and admitted student to the programme based on agreed upon criteria

Payalana dand updated instructional decorps and for students and the applicable agree of the continuous platforms.

Developed and updated instructional documents for students on the online Learning Platform
 Collaborated with the marketing department in creating video marketing campaigns

WHU Otto Beisheim School of Management 11/2016 - 07/2017

Junior Manager, Programme Coordination

· Created and maintained learning schedules for the Bachelor and Master programmes using

university learning platform

 Wrote, edited, and coordinated the development of course catalogues, promotional materials, educational materials, training manuals, newsletters, and/or brochures, as appropriate to the program.

• Developed and administered the online course evaluation tool for students

Updated online lectures and other e-learning materials on the e-learning platform

• Was the point of contact for all external lecturers

Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit 05/2016 - 09/2016

Intern - Department of Education

• Took part in the conception, designing and planning of educational programs in Africa.

• Drew up strategies for implementation of training programs in Sub-Saharan Africa.

Produced and evaluated studies and reports, and compiling project overviews

Conducted gender analyses for vocational education projects

Student Trainee, Personnel department und Courses

**WBS Schulen Dresden** 09/2015 - 02/2016

Coordinated of the study programs

- Organised programs for trainers
- Part of the quality assurance team
- Guidance and counselling for students
- Participated in in the planning and organisation of the personnel development programs.

## **Nairobi Aviation College**

01/2011 - 03/2014

Instructor

- Created learner centered lesson plans that integrated both physical and e-learning aspects
- Delivered relevant insightful lectures to students
- Ensured timely evaluation of learning
- Uploaded e-learning materials to the college learning platform